(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T21:58:20.899749",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ヒトリ
[Song: Alone]
愛されないことは私が
That I wasn't loved...
一番知っていたの
...I knew better than anyone.
それでもあなたはこの痛みに
Even so, to this pain of mine...
意味を与えてくれたから
...you gave meaning,
壊れてしまう恋だとしても
even if it's a love destined to break,
信じた
I wanted to believe...
...んだよ
...you see.
あなたなら 私のすべて
If it were you, I felt like you...
わかってくれる 気がした
...would understand everything about me.
あなたを愛しすぎてしまえば
If I were to love you too much,
あなたをすべて知る前に
before knowing everything about you...
空に願う どうか未来があるように
I pray to the sky, hoping there is a future for us.
今はそう ひとり泣いてるの
Right now, yes, I am crying all alone.
小さな手 私の手にかさねた
Placing your small hand over mine,
あなたの大きな手
your hand felt so big.
失いたくないと願うほど
The more I wished never to lose you,
苦しくなっていたの
the more painful it became.
首についた 真っ赤な愛が
Before the deep red love around my neck...
消える前に あなたに会いたくて
...fades away, I wanted so badly to see you.
目を閉じると 巻き戻される
When I close my eyes, I am rewound...
最後の暖かい夜
...to that last warm night.
その目と優しさと
Those eyes, that kindness,
言葉すべて 嘘じゃない気がして
and all your words—I felt none of it was a lie.
これで最後の恋だと思ったの
I thought this would be my last love,
だから繋ぎ止めていたかったのに
which is why I wanted so badly to hold on to you.
もうすべて分かってるから
Because I already understand everything now,
もう私に近寄らないでよ
please don't come near me anymore.
果てしないこの苦しみまでも
Because there is no one strong enough to love...
愛せるほど強い人はいないから
...even this endless suffering.
あなたを愛しているから
Because I love you,
ずっとあなたが私を忘れるまで
continuously, until you forget about me...
星に願う どうか行かないで
I pray to the stars, "Please don't go."
ずっと私のそばにいてほしい
I want you to stay by my side forever.
あなたを愛しすぎてしまう前に
Before I end up loving you too much,
あなたをすべて知る前に
before knowing everything about you...
空に願う どうか未来があるように
I pray to the sky, hoping there is a future for us.
今はそう ひとり泣いてるの
Right now, yes, I am crying all alone.
今もそう ひとり泣いてるの
Even now, yes, I am crying all alone.
Lagu Tanpa Huruf R
A Song Without the Letter R
Ini kisahnya anak manusia
This is the story of a human child.
Kau bisa memanggilnya dengan nama Iofi
You can call her by the name Iofi.
Sebuah konsonan yang menyulitkan
A troublesome consonant
Membuat lidahnya bosan tak bisa ucapkan
makes her tongue tired of being unable to pronounce it.
Dia coba pahami setiap manusia
She tries to understand every human being.
Punya hebat punya cacat
Everyone has their strengths and flaws.
Possessing greatness, possessing flaws.
Dia coba nikmati hidup ini cuma sekali
She tries to enjoy this life, given only once.
Dia hanya punya modal cinta
She only has love to offer,
Yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
which she pours into every song.
Tak inginkan semua 'tuk suka
She doesn't expect everyone to like her;
Dia hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
she only wants to write songs
Tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
about everything inside her heart.
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, that's perfectly fine.
Sejak kecil dia punya mimpi
Ever since she was little, she had a dream
Jadi musisi atau apapun di bidang seni
to become a musician or work in the arts.
Tumbuh dewasa bulatlah sudah
As she grew up, her mind was set:
Keputusannya 'tuk dapatkan mimpinya
her decision to achieve her dream.
Dia coba pahami setiap manusia
She tries to understand every person,
Punya hebat punya cacat
with their strengths and flaws.
Dia coba nikmati hidup ini cuma sekali
She tries to enjoy this life, given only once.
Dia hanya punya modal cinta
She only has love to offer,
Yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
which she pours into every song.
Tak inginkan semua 'tuk suka
She doesn't expect everyone to like her;
Dia hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
she only wants to write songs
Tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
about everything inside her heart.
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, that's perfectly fine.
Dia hanya punya modal cinta
She only has love to offer,
Yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
which she pours into every song.
Tak inginkan semua 'tuk suka
She doesn't expect everyone to like her;
Dia hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
she only wants to write songs
Tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
about everything inside her heart.
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, that's perfectly fine.
Hanya punya modal cinta
Only having love to offer,
Yang dia embuskan dalam setiap lagunya
which she pours into every song.
Tak inginkan semua 'tuk suka
She doesn't expect everyone to like her;
Dia hanya ingin tuliskan lagu
she only wants to write songs
Tentang semua yang ada dalam hatinya
about everything inside her heart.
Bila tak suka tentu saja tak mengapa
If you don't like it, that's perfectly fine.
Ioforia, Obisa, halo~
Ioforia, Obisa, hello~
Aku Airani Iofifteen dari Hololive Indonesia First Generation!
I'm Airani Iofifteen from Hololive Indonesia 1st Generation!
Halo, selamat datang di Birthday Live!
Hello, welcome to my Birthday Live!
And by the way, the hashtag is #iofiLucidDream, you can just tweet all of you can, okay?
And by the way, the hashtag is #iofiLucidDream. You can tweet as much as you can, okay?
And by the way, 気づいた人もいると思うんで、あのさっきの曲、Rがないんですよ！
And by the way, I think some of you noticed, that song earlier had no "R"s in it!
Hai! There's no R whatsoever!
Yes! There's no "R" whatsoever!
Jadi kalian kalau misalkan kalian sama cadel kayak aku, kalian bisa nyanyi lagu ini karena gak ada R-nya.
So if you happen to have a lisp like me, you can sing this song since there are no "R"s.
Tapi bagi yang gak... apa ya? Bagi yang gak nyadar, nanti akan keluar versi cover song-nya.
But for those who... what is it? For those who didn't notice, the cover song version will be out later.
そのカバー曲の場所もあるので、後でまた見てね！
The details for the cover song are also available, so please check it out later!
And by the way, by the way, this guitar...
実はね、家でもさ、このモデルとこの色のギター持ってるんですよ！改めて見てください！
Actually, I have a guitar with this exact model and color at home too! Take a look again!
Hi, if you remember, I kind of uploaded this guitar picture somewhere, yes!
Hi, if you remember, I uploaded a picture of this guitar somewhere, yes!
Tapi biasanya aku main gitar cuma di membership, ya.
But usually, I only play guitar in membership streams.
Jadi ini pertama kali aku main gitar selain di membership.
So this is the first time I'm playing guitar outside of membership streams.
I guess.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
そう、あの面限の皆はもう知ってると思うん...マッスけど！
Well, I think everyone from the members-only streams already knows...
あの、普通はギターは面限でしか弾いてないんだけど
Usually, I've only played the guitar in members-only streams,
これが、面限じゃなく配信で初めてです！
but this is the first time playing it on a public stream!
いや、ちょっと... 怖いんだけど...
Well, I'm a bit... nervous...
まあまあまあ...
But well, well...
どうでしたか？
How was it?
どう？どう？
How is it? How is it?
かわいい？かわいい？
Is it cute? Is it cute?
いっぱいスクショ撮った？スクショ撮った？
Did you take lots of screenshots? Did you take screenshots?
I hope you enjoy it!
I hope you enjoyed it!
And by the way, we still have a lot more going on.
So after this, there's gonna be a lot and a lot of guests.
So please wait for it.
ね、この後もゲストが盛りだくさんなので！
There will be plenty of guests coming up after this!
楽しみにしててくだいねー！
So please look forward to it, okay?
Don't forget to take a lot of screenshots!
かわいい？
Cute?
Lagi? Lagi? Lucu? Lucu? Lucu? Lucu?
More? More? Cute? Cute? Cute? Cute?
まあね、時間があればこれもね、またギター弾きたいなと思っております！
Well, if there's time, I'd like to play the guitar again!
はい！
Alright!
あ！
Ah!
OK? 準備OK?
OK? Ready?
OK, OK, OK? OK?
あ、OK！Sip!
Ah, OK! Got it!
では、ゲストパートに...
Now then, for the guest part...
また会おうね！
See you again soon!
Thank you! See you guys in guest part!
Thank you! See you guys in the guest part!
THERE IS A REASON
[Song: THERE IS A REASON]
どこから話せばいいんだろう
Where should I begin talking?
待ちくたびれても
Even if you're tired of waiting,
終わりだなんて言わせないから
I won't let you say it's over.
書きなぐった無意識の衝動を連れ
Driven by scribbled, unconscious impulses,
何もかも壊したら
once everything has been destroyed,
不可動を始めればいいんだ
we just have to start the impossible.
There's a reason that we came across in this world
There's a reason that we caught the magnetic wave
傷つけ合う世界はどこへ
Where is this world of mutual hurt heading?
So 愛のために泣けるのは 君がそこにいるから
So, the reason I can cry for love is because you are there.
君だけを呼び続けるから
Because I will keep calling out only to you,
愛のために歌うのは そして共に行き抜くこと
the reason I sing for love is to survive together with you.
ずっと君と...
Always with you...
青色した空と波ひとつない鏡のような海を見てた
Looking at the blue sky and the mirror-like sea without a single wave,
どんな場所にいたって どんな形になって どんな時代にいたって
no matter where we are, what form we take, or what era we live in,
見つけ出すよ
I will find you,
定めに逆らって
resisting our fate.
There's a reason that we came across in this world
There's a reason that we caught the magnetic wave
引き寄せ合う二人はどこへ
Where are we two, drawing close to each other, heading?
So 愛のために進むのは 君とここにいるから
So, the reason I move forward for love is because I am here with you.
僕だけが君を守るから
Because I alone will protect you,
愛のために願うのは そして誰も傷つけずに
the reason I pray for love is so no one gets hurt,
ずっと隣で...
always by your side...
僕らは超えてゆく
We will go beyond...
すべての憎しみを
all the hatred,
ニセモノの正義など捨ててしまえ
casting away fake justice.
So 愛のために泣けるのは 君がそこにいるから
So, the reason I can cry for love is because you are there.
We will always be together
We'll always be together
愛のために進むのは
The reason I move forward for love
君とここにいるから
is because I am here with you.
僕だけが君を守るから
Because I alone will protect you.
愛のために願うのは
The reason I wish for love
そして共に生き抜く事
is to survive together.
ずっと
Always...
We'll always be together
やったー！誕生日おめでとう！
Yay! Happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
今年も来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming again this year!
どうもこんにちは、ときのそらです！よろしくお願いします！
Hello everyone, I'm Tokino Sora! It's great to be here!
いやー、なんかね、バラード歌っちゃったね。
Wow, we ended up singing a ballad, huh?
ねー！
Yeah!
より、私すごい気になってんだけど...
More than that, I've been really curious...
な、何これ？
W-What is this?
焚き火！
A campfire!
いいの、宇宙寒いくらいだから、これ温かいよ。
Well, space gets pretty cold, so this keeps us warm!
え、宇宙で焚き火なんてできるんだね？
Wait, you can make a campfire in space?
できるよ、一応！
You can, sort of!
だって、酸素があるってことだ。
I mean, that implies there's oxygen.
あ、でもでも、酸素いるからさ、今これバリアーあるから。
Ah, but there's oxygen inside because we're inside a barrier now.
そう、酸素ないんだったらもう燃えないジャン。
Yeah, if there wasn't oxygen, it wouldn't burn.
あ、まあそうだね！そうだよね！
Ah, well, that's true! You're right!
うん、そう、温かくてよくね？
Yeah, so isn't it nice and cozy?
MCでこんなにまったり焚き火の前で...
Having such a chill talk in front of a campfire during an MC...
こう、夜に二人で喋っちゃうみたいな雰囲気でやることないよ！
...feeling like two people just chatting late at night... We never do this!
ないから、ちょっと変な感じがする！
Since we don't, it feels a little strange!
あ、そうだね。普通にポーズスタートに「はー、ありがとう！歌ったね」っていう...
Ah, true. Usually we'd start with a pose and say, "Phew, thanks! We sang!"
すぐだけど、やっぱり今年のテーマもっとゆるいとか落ち着く雰囲気ほしいから...
Right, but this year's theme is more chill and relaxing...
そのダンスと歌のあとにマイクをね、ちょっと落としてここに座ってるというね。
We wanted that kind of atmosphere, so after dancing and singing, we set down our mics and sat down here.
でもいいね、まったりできるから、ちょっとのんびりしておしゃべりできる感じいいと思う。
But it's nice! Since we can chill, being able to relax and chat like this feels great.
でね、今年誕生日に２回目...来てんだよね、毎年。
And you know, this is the second time you've come for my birthday... every year!
去年と一昨年ってこと？
You mean last year and the year before?
そうそうそう！
Yes, exactly!
今年で、来年も来る？
And this year too. Will you come next year as well?
え、もちろん、もちろん！呼んでもらえればいつでも行くよ！
Of course, of course! Whenever you invite me, I'll be there!
あ、やったー！じゃあ決定でーす！
Yay! Then it's decided!
そしたら、去年と今年も結構ハンドマイクでやってるから...
So, since last year and this year we've been using handheld mics...
聴かせるみたいな感じの曲が多かったよね。
...we've had many songs meant for sitting back and listening.
じゃあ、来年はバリバリ踊ります？そしたら。
Then next year, shall we dance with full energy instead?
いいねー！踊り、やっぱり姉さん好き？踊るの。
Sounds good! Big sister, do you like dancing after all?
大好き！イオフィーは？
I love it! What about you, Iofi?
好き好き好き！ね、いいよね！
I love it too! Isn't it great?
いや、でもさ、今年のテーマさっきも聞いて、バラードだって聞いて...
Though, hearing about this year's theme and that it's ballads...
バラードの全体をライブするのってすごい難しいなって私は思っちゃうの。
...I personally think hosting an entire live performance with ballads is really difficult.
演出とかもそうだけどさ...
With the staging and everything...
私いつもダンスとかで見せるのをやるから、バラードで挑戦するのってすごいなって思ってて。
I usually perform by showing off dance routines, so I think taking on the challenge of ballads is amazing.
あー、そー、でも自分にとってはバラードが一番声に似合うから...
Ah~ I see. But for me, ballads suit my voice the best...
そう、もっと魅せたいなとは思ってて...
...so I really wanted to show more of that side.
そう、だからね... ほら、見える！いっぱい！うわー、綺麗！宇宙！
Yeah, so... Look, you can see so much! Wow, so pretty! Space!
宇宙に来ました。去年も一応は宇宙にいたんだけど...
We came to space. Last year, well, we were technically in space...
あんまり見えないかもしれないな、それが。だから今年はちゃんと宇宙に来たー！って...
...it might not have been very visible. So this year, we really came to space!
うわー、すごーい！宇宙来ました、二人で。
Wow, amazing! The two of us came to space.
綺麗！本当に！姉さんと似合うんじゃない？
It's so pretty! Really! Doesn't it suit you, big sister?
そう、普通イメージカラーが青だから、ほら、青のステージも、こっちも。
Yeah, since your image color is blue, see, the blue stage is like this, too.
へえー、いいな、かわいいなー！
Heh~ Nice, it's so cute!
みんなもいっぱいスクショ撮った？
Did everyone take lots of screenshots too?
撮った！
I did!
撮ったー！
We took 'em!
似合うでしょう？ほら、めっちゃ可愛い！
Looks good on us, right? See, super cute!
ふぁんふぁんして！
Do the fluttery pose!
おおー！
Ooh!
可愛いー！
So cute!
おっ！もっと見せて？あっ！
Oh! Show me more? Ah!
ねぇ、これ私の記念日じゃないんだ！
Wait, this isn't my anniversary stream!
そうだね！
That's right!
いおりん！
Iofi-rin!
大丈夫だよ！はい！いっぱい撮りました！二人で！
It's fine! Yes, we took lots of photos together!
ういー！
Yay!
はい、ということで今回はまだまだ言えるので、皆さんも楽しみにしてください！
Alright, so there's still plenty more to come, everyone please look forward to it!
ねー！本当におめでとうだよー！
Yeah! Really, congratulations!
では、来年また歌って踊ろうね！
Let's sing and dance together again next year!
はい！で、皆さんありがとう！ありがとうございました！
Yes! And thank you everyone! Thank you so much!
またねー！バイバイー！
See you later! Bye-bye!
幸せになって
[Song: Be Happy]
何度も問いかけた
I asked myself time and time again,
自問自答繰り返した先に
after repeating these inner questions over and over.
答えがあるのなら
If there truly is an answer,
このまま探してみようか
shall we try searching for it like this?
あなたの胸の中に
Inside your heart,
私は少しでも居れたのかな
was I able to stay even for a little while?
あなたの居ない世界は
A world without you...
想像さえ出来なかった
I couldn't even begin to imagine it.
もしもあなたが
If at the exact moment...
あの子を選んだ瞬間に
...you chose her,
私が頭の中
...I had crossed...
駆け巡っていたのなら
...your mind...
悔しいな
...that would be so frustrating.
こんなにもあなたのこと
Before I fell this deeply...
好きになってしまう前に
...in love with you,
せめてさ
at least...
サヨナラの言葉 告げてほしかったなんて
...I wished you'd told me goodbye.
勝手でワガママだよね
I know that's selfish and demanding of me.
誰より想っているのに
Even though I care for you more than anyone,
あなたを世界で一番笑顔に変えられる人はきっと
the person who can make you smile most in the world...
私じゃないから
...is surely not me.
どうか幸せになって
Please, be happy.
どんなに願っても
No matter how much I pray,
変わりはしないこの現実が
this reality that will never change...
ただただ目の前の
...snatched away...
光すべて奪い去った
...all the light right in front of my eyes.
生まれ変わっても
Even if I were reborn,
もう一度あなたに恋するのかな
would I fall in love with you all over again?
そんなのさ…なんて
Something like that...
考えることすらもバカみたい
Even thinking about it feels foolish.
こんなにもあなたのこと
Before I fell this deeply...
好きになってしまう前に
...in love with you,
わざとさ
intentionally...
優しい言葉で勘違いさせないでって
...don't lead me on with kind words.
勝手でワガママだよね
I know that's selfish and demanding of me.
あなたの幸せそうな
Just seeing your happy face...
顔を見るだけで胸いっぱいになる
...fills my heart to the brim.
あなたと私はきっと
Because you and I...
お似合いじゃないから
...are surely not meant to be.
どうか幸せになって
Please, be happy.
涙出るのは
The reason tears fall...
嘘でも強がるから
...is because I act tough even with lies.
気づかないフリしないで
Don't pretend you don't notice.
どうしても諦められないよ
I just can't give up on you,
終わった恋なのに
even though this love is over.
こんなにもあなたのこと…
Even though I love you so much...
好きになってしまう前に
Before I completely fall in love with you,
せめてさ
at the very least...
さよならの言葉 告げてほしかったなって
...I wish you had said goodbye to me.
勝手でわがままだよね
I'm just being selfish and demanding, aren't I?
こんなにもあなたのこと
Even though I care about you...
好きになってしまう前に
...this much, before I fall completely in love,
せめてさ さよならの言葉
at least say the word "goodbye"...
告げてほしかったなって 勝手でわがままだよね
...I wish you had told me. I know it's selfish of me.
誰より思ってるのに
Even though I love you more than anyone,
あなたを世界で
in this world,
一番笑顔に変えられる人は
the person who can make you smile the most...
私じゃないから
...isn't me.
だから 幸せになって
That's why... please be happy.
幸せになって
Please be happy.
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming!
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
イエーイ！おめでとう！
Yay! Congratulations!
では最初は誰から自己紹介する？
So, who wants to introduce themselves first?
じゃあ俺から行こうかな。
Well, shall I go first then?
ホロスターズ1期生の律可です！よろしくお願いします！
I'm Rikka from Holostars 1st Generation! Nice to meet you!
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい、ホロスターズ3期生、TriNeroの影山シエンです！よろしくお願いします！
Hi! I'm Kageyama Shien from Holostars 3rd Generation, TriNero! Nice to meet you!
よろしくおねがいしまーす！イエーイ！
Nice to meet you! Yay!
一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう、本当に！
Thank you so much for singing with me today, really!
いやいや、呼んでくれてありがとう！嬉しかった！
No no, thank you for inviting us! We were so happy!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
なんか律可先輩からは、私がデビューの頃結構お世話になってて、私が…
Rikka-senpai supported me a lot around my debut time, and I...
一コラボとか来てもらったりしたもんね。
Yeah, you came over for our first collab and all.
そうそう。なので、なんか今回歌いたいなと思ってて。
Right, right. So I really wanted to sing together this time.
おー、ありがとうね！呼んでくれてありがとう！
Oh, thank you! Thanks for having us!
シエンくんは…
And Shien-kun...
後輩だもんね。
He's a junior, right?
そうそうそう！
Right, right, right!
なんかスタジオで会った時にさ、仕事で。たまたま気楽に…
When we happened to run into each other at the studio for work...
「じゃあ次の来年の誕生日に来てくれる？」って…
I casually asked, "Would you come to my next birthday event next year?"
そう言ってくれて！スタジオでホントにバッタリ会って、「まさか本当に呼んでもらえるとは！」って！
You asked me! We bumped into each other at the studio, and I couldn't believe you actually invited me!
え、信じられなかったの？！
Eh, you didn't believe me?!
いやいや！もう嬉しすぎてびっくりしちゃったよ僕！ありがとうございます！
No, no! I was just so happy and surprised! Thank you so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
え、僕たち揃うのが…2年前ぶり？
Wait, the three of us gathering like this... is it for the first time in 2 years?
だいぶ久しぶりだね！
It's been quite a while!
ホロスターズ側のカウントダウンライブで、この3人とコボちゃんで歌わせていただいたんですけど…
At the Holostars countdown live, the three of us and Kobo-chan sang together...
一緒に歌うのは実はそれぶり！
So singing together is actually for the first time since then!
それぶり！
Since then!
2年前！もう2年経った…！
2 years ago! 2 years have already passed...!
そう、2年経ったんだなーって感じ。
Yeah, it really feels like 2 years have passed.
早いなー！ / 早い！ / 早いですね！
Time flies so fast!
でも一緒に歌えてめちゃめちゃ楽しかったです！
But singing together was so much fun!
なんか3人バンドみたいだったよね！
It felt like a 3-piece band!
ギター1人、ボーカル2人みたいな！
Like 1 guitarist and 2 vocalists!
見たことある感じの絵面だった。
It was a visual setup you often see.
来年だったらもうバンドやります？そしたら。
Shall we do a full band next year then?
じゃあ僕ドラムやろうかな！
I'll play the drums then!
ドラム？！ / そしたらなんかいい感じじゃん。じゃあ俺トライアングルやるわ。
Drums?! / Then that sounds neat. I'll play the triangle then.
なんで？！ / なんでそっちやるの？！
Why?! / Why are you playing that?!
マラカス？
Maracas?
リズム隊いらないじゃん！ / リズム隊じゃん！ほとんど聞こえないけど！ / ギターとかいないんだ。
We'd have no rhythm section! / That IS a rhythm section! Though you'd barely hear it! / And no guitarists at all.
トライアングルとか思わなかったな。鳴らすだけだから。
I didn't expect a triangle. Since you just chime it.
気持ちでタンバリンにしようかな。
Maybe I'll go with a tambourine instead based on feeling.
タンバリンね。タンバリンで… / みんなうるさいやつじゃん！
Tambourine, huh? / Then everyone's playing loud instruments!
シャンシャンシャンシャン！ / 今回結構しっとりだったから。
*Cling cling cling cling!* / Since it was quite gentle this time.
誰かわかんないですけどね、流石にね。 / でもハモり難しかったね、やっぱりね。
We wouldn't know who's who. / But harmony was really tough, as expected.
3人だからさー。 / そう、なんか元々男性と女性が…
Because there are three of us. / Yeah, originally a male and female...
2人で歌う曲を探すのって、結構難しくて。
...finding a song that a guy and a girl can sing together is pretty difficult.
確かにね。キーがね。 / うん、キーが。
True. The key range. / Yeah, the key.
女性の曲だからキー下げなきゃいけないし、下げたらこっちが低すぎるから…
It's a female song, so we have to lower the key, but lowering it makes it too low for me...
「どうしよう？！」ってなって。
...so I was like, "What should we do?!"
めちゃめちゃステキな曲！ / 原曲の雰囲気もすごく良かった！ / ありがとう！
It's such a wonderful song! / The vibe of the original song was great too! / Thank you!
ゲストは、最初には「絶対に律可くんとシエン先輩を招待したい！」って…
For guests, at first I was like, "I definitely want to invite Rikka-kun and Shien-senpai!"
招待したんだけど、その時期に曲がまだ決まってなくて。 / あ、そうだったんだ！
So I invited you, but at that time the song wasn't decided yet. / Ah, is that so!
後から決まったんだ。 / 後から！ / いい曲見つけたね！
It was decided afterwards. / Afterwards! / You found a great song!
本当に良かったよー！ / 声にも合ってたし、この3人の雰囲気がめちゃめちゃ良かった！
I'm really glad! / It fit your voices so well, and the vibe of us three was awesome!
本当に良かったー！
I'm so glad!
ゲストが決まって、その曲って感じ。
First the guests were set, and then the song.
なるほどね！ / いやー、またやりたいけどね！
I see! / Man, I'd love to do this again!
次はバンド？
Is a band next?
バンドやるか！ マラカス...
Shall we form a band? Maracas...
練習時間めっちゃかかりそうだけどな。
Practice time is gonna take forever, though.
確かに。
True.
ドラムやったことないからな。
I've never played drums before.
やるの？
Are we doing it?
やるしかない！
We have no choice!
やるなら練習しますよ！
If we do it, we'll practice!
じゃあ来年やります、バンド！
Then next year we'll do a band!
本当にやりそうだからな。
Because they'll actually make it happen.
ということで来年楽しみに...
So look forward to next year...
みんな本気にするよ、これ。
Everyone's gonna take this seriously.
怖い、怖い！
Scary, scary!
では来年お楽しみにということで！
So please look forward to next year!
本当にみんな見てくれてありがとう！
Thank you everyone so much for watching!
これからもまだまだあるので 楽しんでください！
There's still so much more coming, so please enjoy!
楽しんでね！ バイバイ！
Have fun! Bye-bye!
ぼくらのレッドイットビー
[Title: Bokura no Let It Be]
生まれ変われるのなら
If maybe we could be born once again,
目印になるから
so it can serve as a marker,
巻いておこう
let's wrap it around.
小指と小指の長い糸
The long thread between our pinkies,
ほどけないように
so that it won't untie,
結んでおこう
let's tie it tight.
夏祭り
Summer festival,
りんご飴
candy apples...
雨降り空に 虹がかかる頃なのかな
Is it around the time when a rainbow spans across the rainy sky?
壊れた感情が いつか君を消していく
Broken emotions will someday erase you.
見えなくなると 失われる灯火
When you can no longer be seen, the light is lost.
でも 結んだ長い糸 ほどけ落ちていないから
But the long thread we tied hasn't unraveled,
また ぼくたちは 出会う時が来る きっと
so the time will surely come for us to meet again.
ぼくら 大人になったら
When we grow up,
正義のヒーローになるんだ
we'll become heroes of justice.
地球の平和を守るのさ
We'll protect the peace of the Earth.
探検しようぜ おばけ屋敷
Let's go explore the haunted house.
でも本当は 怖くて泣き虫
But truth is, I was scared and a crybaby.
一緒に居たいだけ
I just wanted to be together.
明日も晴れて 空を青く照らせば
If tomorrow is clear and lights up the sky in blue,
ぼくらは ここに 秘密基地を作ろう
let's build a secret base right here.
そして探検しよう 雨ならゲームをしよう
And let's go exploring, or play games if it rains.
そんな時間が ずっと続くはずだったんだ
Such times were supposed to go on forever.
悪者は ぼくだった
I was the bad guy.
逃げたのは ぼくだ
I was the one who ran away.
嘘じゃない 本物の嘘つきだ
It's no lie, I'm a real liar.
花束に包まれて
Wrapped in a bouquet of flowers,
目を瞑る君は
closing your eyes, you were
安らかに 清らかに
peacefully, purely
眠っていたんだ
sleeping.
壊れた感情が いつか君を消していこう
Broken emotions will someday erase you.
失う前に 消えてしまう前に
Before losing you, before you disappear,
ただ 結んだ長い糸 ほどけ落ちていなかった
the long thread we tied hadn't unravelled.
きっと ぼくたちは...
Surely, we...
いつのときが来る きっと
A time will surely come...
Lama ku memendam rasa di dada
I've held these feelings inside my chest for so long
Mengagumi indahmu, wahai jelita
Admiring your beauty, oh beautiful one
Tak dapat lagi ku ucap kata
I can no longer utter a word
Bisuku diam terpesona
Silent and spellbound in awe
Dan andai suatu hari kau jadi milikku
And if one day you become mine
Tak akan kulepas dirimu, oh kasih
I won't let you go, oh my love
Dan bila waktu mengizinkanku untuk menunggu dirimu
And if time allows me to wait for you
Kurasa ku tlah jatuh cinta
I think I've fallen in love
Pada pandangan yang pertama
At first sight
Sulit bagiku untuk bisa
It's hard for me to be able to
Berhenti mengagumi dirinya
Stop admiring her
Seiring dengan berjalannya waktu
As time goes by
Akhirnya kita berdua bertemu
Finally the two of us met
Oh diriku tersipu malu
Oh, I was blushing shyly
Melihat sikapmu yang lucu
Seeing your cute behavior
Dan andai suatu hari kau jadi milikku
And if one day you become mine
Tak akan kulepas dirimu, oh kasih
I won't let you go, oh my love
Dan bila waktu mengizinkanku menunggu dirimu
And if time allows me to wait for you
Kurasa ku tlah jatuh cinta
I think I've fallen in love
Pada pandangan yang pertama
At first sight
Sulit bagiku untuk bisa
It's hard for me to be able to
Berhenti mengagumi dirinya
Stop admiring her
Oh Tuhan tolong diriku
Oh God, please help me
Tuk membuat dia menjadi milikku
To make her mine
Sayangku, kasihku, oh cintaku
My darling, my love, oh my sweetheart
She's all that I need
Dan bila kita bersama
And when we are together
Kan kujaga dirimu untuk selamanya
I will protect you forever
Oh terima cintaku
Oh, please accept my love
Summertime, ain't a summertime
If I don't have you as mine, but you're always on my mind, yeah
In the magazine you showed up
Baby girl, your beauty makes my mind blow up
Your personality, it's calm and friendly
The kinda girl that I would love to be with me
Once I start, no, I won't fall back
Here's my cellphone number, so please call back, come on!
Kurasa ku tlah jatuh cinta
I think I've fallen in love
Pada pandangan yang pertama
At first sight
Sulit bagiku untuk bisa
It's hard for me to be able to
Berhenti mengagumi dirinya
Stop admiring her
Oh Tuhan tolong diriku
Oh God, please help me
Tuk membuat dia menjadi milikku
To make her mine
Sayangku, kasihku, oh cintaku
My darling, my love, oh my sweetheart
She's all that I need
Pesawat Kertas 365 Hari
[Title: 365 Days of Paper Airplanes]
Ku tatap langit di pagi hari
I look up at the morning sky
Ku awali hari dengan doa
I start the day with a prayer
Semoga satu hari ini bisa
Wishing that today can be
Dipenuhi oleh senyum
Filled with smiles
Walaupun terkadang hujan turun
Even though it rains sometimes
Dan air mata juga mengalir
And tears flow down as well
Di hari yang tak berjalan dengan mulus
On days that don't go smoothly
Besok pun tetap semangat
Keep your spirits up for tomorrow
Di dalam mimpiku selalu
In my dreams, I always see
Terlihat ada diriku sendiri
Myself existing freely
Yang dengan bebasnya
Doing everything freely
Melakukan semua hal yang ingin aku lakukan
Everything that I want to do
Hidup bagaikan pesawat kertas
Life is like a paper airplane
Terbang dan pergi membawa impian
Flying away carrying dreams
Sekuat tenaga dengan hembusan angin
With all its strength in the breeze
Terus melaju terbang
It keeps flying forward
Jangan bandingkan jarak terbangnya
Don't compare how far it flies
Tapi bagaimana dan apa yang dilalui
But how and what it went through
Karena itulah satu hal yang penting
Because that's the one important thing
S'lalu sesuai kata hati
Always following your heart
Sanbyaku rokujugo nichi
365 days
Di saat terlihat bintang-bintang
When the stars are visible
Atau malam yang gelap gulita
Or on pitch-black nights
Pada saat semangatmu hilang
When you lose your motivation
Carilah orang lain dan bicara
Find someone and talk to them
Manusia tidaklah pernah
Humans are never
Ditinggal sendirian saja
Truly left all alone
Terkadang kita tak menyadari
Sometimes we fail to notice
Hal baik di sekitar kita
The good things around us
Hidup bagaikan pesawat kertas
Life is like a paper airplane
Terbang dan membawa cinta kita semua
Flying and carrying all our love
Sayap yang terbentang dengan percaya diri
Wings spread out with confidence
Dilihat semua orang
Seen by everyone
Walau tak tahu cara melipatnya
Even if you don't know how to fold it
Suatu saat pasti akan berhasil lalu terbang
Someday it will succeed and fly
Kekuatan harapan yang menerbangkannya
The power of hope makes it fly
Ya, mari nikmatilah
Yes, let's enjoy it
Sanbyaku rokujugo nichi
365 days
Hidup bagaikan pesawat kertas
Life is like a paper airplane
Terbang dan pergi membawa impian
Flying away carrying dreams
Sekuat tenaga dengan hembusan angin
With all its strength in the breeze
Terus melaju terbang
It keeps flying forward
Jangan bandingkan jarak terbangnya
Don't compare how far it flies
Tapi bagaimana dan apa yang dilalui
But how and what it went through
Karena itulah satu hal yang penting
Because that's the one important thing
S'lalu sesuai kata hati
Always following your heart
Sanbyaku rokujugo nichi
365 days
Ayo terbanglah (Coba terbanglah)
Come on, fly! (Try to fly!)
Ayo terbanglah
Come on, fly!
Coba terbanglah
Try to fly!
Ayo terbanglah
Come on, fly!
Coba terbanglah
Try to fly!
Aku dapet!
I got it!
Yada!
Yay!
Halo semuanya!
Hello, everyone!
Oh my god, lu keliatan gwedeng!
Oh my god, you look so big!
Hai! Hai!
Hi! Hi!
Akhirnya ya, Pia, kolab kecil-kecilan kita
Finally, Pia, our small collab
nggak kecil, udah jadi besar, guys!
isn't small anymore, it's become big, guys!
Yeah, finally!
Terima kasih su- Berdiri deh.
Thank you so- Stand up.
Jadi, terima kasih sudah mengundang saya, Senpai!
So, thank you for inviting me, Senpai!
Oya, Senpai? Iya Senpai! Ulang tahun yang ke berapa, Senpai?
Oh, Senpai? Yes, Senpai! Which anniversary is it, Senpai?
Enam!
Six!
Tapi kok belum lulus-lulus juga?
But why haven't you graduated yet?
Daripada gitu, mending jikoushōkai dulu, ayo!
Rather than that, let's do self-introductions first, come on!
We are ON FIRE!
Semangat membara siap menghangatkan hari-harimu!
A burning spirit ready to warm your days!
Halo, aku Piacolo dari JK Tiga Lima Virtual Generation generasi pertama! Halo semuanya!
Hello, I'm Piacolo from JK35 Virtual Generation Gen 1! Hello, everyone!
Oh my god, yes!
Anyway, aku nyadar sesuatu, tahu enggak?
Anyway, I realized something, you know?
Apa?
What?
Sorry ya! Basically buat kalian yang bilang aku lebih pendek...
Sorry, okay! Basically for those of you who said I was shorter...
Now you guys see...
Halah, dikit doang!
Come on, it's just a little bit!
Dikit doang means everything to me, you know! Means everything!
Just a little bit means everything to me, you know! Means everything!
Enggak, enggak, enggak, heels-nya doang. Heels-nya berapa?
No, no, no, it's just the heels. How tall are the heels?
Uh, okay, duduk aja yuk!
Uh, okay, let's just sit down!
Well, for your information, enggak banyak kok, paling 18 cm.
Well, for your information, it's not much, at most 18 cm.
Tapi-tapi ya, kaki aku enggak nyampe.
But-but, my feet can't reach the floor.
See?
Guys, dia- dia tuh emang... Look at that!
Guys, she's really... Look at that!
Ngambang, cuy! Bro, ngambang for no reason! Anjir, lah!
Floating, dude! Bro, floating for no reason! Holy crap!
Anjir, enggak nyampe!
Damn, can't reach!
Yep, beda kan?
Yep, see the difference?
これ！
This!
私、これ！
Me, this!
見て！
Look!
届かない！
Can't reach!
Okelah. Oh my god!
Okay then. Oh my god!
Jadi ya, untuk lagu ini ya, by the way, koreografinya Fritschie.
So yeah, for this song, by the way, the choreography is by Fritschie.
Aku dikasih tahu sama Pia. Pia-kara oshiete moraimashita.
Pia told me. Pia taught me.
Chorus, itu favorit banget enggak sih?
The chorus, isn't that a total favorite?
Coba, one more, gimana, gimana beat-nya?
Try one more time, how does the beat go?
Aaah! Kawaii!
Aaah! So cute!
Kawaii! Lucu banget kan?
So cute! Isn't it super cute?
Asik, asik!
Awesome, awesome!
Ya, jadi gitu.
Yeah, so it's like that.
Guys, tolong don't judge me.
Guys, please don't judge me.
Don't judge me, we're learning, okay? We're learning, ya.
Don't judge me, we're learning, okay? We're learning.
Ya, learning. Jadi kalau ada yang apa-apa-apa-apa, ya ke Pia.
Yeah, learning. So if there's anything wrong, go to Pia.
Gak gitu ya! Gak gitu!
Not like that! Not like that!
Anyway, what is this?
Karena kamu mau ke sini, aku prepare ini.
Because you were coming here, I prepared this.
Really? Is this like for me?
Yeah, coba, coba. Coba dekat-dekat cium.
Yeah, try it, try it. Try getting close and smelling it.
We are ON FIRE!
I'm so honored, guys.
Mm, bau gue!
Mm, smells like me!
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry!
Jadi kalau kalian penasaran, ini baunya Pia kayak gini, guys.
So if you guys are curious, Pia smells like this, guys.
Ya, bau arang!
Yeah, smells like charcoal!
Bau abu, bau arang tuh bau gue, cuy!
Ash smell, charcoal smell is my smell, dude!
Tapi lucu, kan?
But it's cute, right?
Kore wa, um, lucu, lucu!
This is, um, cute, cute!
Aku suka banget! Enggak mau pulang, boleh enggak?
I really love it! Can I not go home?
Enggak mau pulang? Atau gue di sini, gue jadi tukang kabel juga enggak apa-apa deh.
Don't want to go home? Or I can stay here, I can be a cable technician, that's fine too.
Serius nih.
Seriously.
Tapi iya, terima kasih ya untuk manajemennya Pia sudah apa...
But yeah, thank you to Pia's management for...
meminjamkan saya Pia.
lending me Pia.
Bercanda! Terima kasih buat Host, Staff, Management, terima kasih.
Just kidding! Thank you to the Host, Staff, Management, thank you.
Iya, Kak. Iya, Kak. Hehehe.
Yes, Sis. Yes, Sis. Hehehe.
Yeah, oh my god, I cannot really... Oh my god.
Oshiku, akhirnya aku bisa memanggil kamu, tahu enggak, guys?
My oshi, I can finally invite you, you know, guys?
Aku tuh guys, waktu pertama kali dibilang, "Aku mau invite kamu," aku kayak...
Guys, when she first told me, "I want to invite you," I was like...
何？！
What?!
Aku kayak... Terus manager-ku kayak, "Kalau bisa aku pegang, kayak wuaaah!"
I was like... Then my manager was like, "If I could hold her, it'd be like whoaaah!"
"Aku diundang sama oshiku!" gitu.
"I was invited by my oshi!" like that.
Iya, begitu. Tapi ya...
Yeah, like that. But yeah...
Tapi aku walaupun excited, harus pulang, Bro.
But even though I'm excited, I have to go home, Bro.
Oh iya, benar. Aw, thank you for coming!
Oh yeah, true. Aw, thank you for coming!
Yeah, it's okay, thank you! You know, enjoy the rest of the show.
I will watch from there.
Okay, see ya!
Cepat-cepat, bye-bye! Bye-bye, arigatou, thank you!
Hurry, hurry, bye-bye! Bye-bye, thank you, thank you!
Yoha! Ovisa! Kita sudah di penghujung acara nih, guys.
Yoha! Ovisa! We're at the end of the show, guys.
Tapi sebelum kita ke akhir acara, aku akan berterima kasih dulu.
But before we reach the end of the show, I want to say thank you first.
Terima kasih sudah datang.
Thank you for coming.
Frane-sama, arigatou! Dekapas-sama, arigatou! Ryo-kun mo arigatou! Pia juga terima kasih dan Risu-dono...
Frane-sama, thank you! Dekapas-sama, thank you! Ryo-kun as well, thank you! Pia as well, thank you, and Risu-dono...
Nah, terima kasih semuanya~
Well, thank you everyone~
Iya, akhirnya ya. Iofi Birthday Celebration 2025
Yeah, finally. Iofi Birthday Celebration 2025
sudah di penghujung acara.
is coming to an end.
Tapi jangan skip ads dulu!
But don't skip the ads just yet!
Sebelum berakhir, aku punya sesuatu untuk kalian.
Before it ends, I have something for you guys.
では、Birthday goods! Tada! Ta-bang!
So, birthday goods! Tada! Ta-bang!
Hai! Iofi Birthday 2025,
Yes! Iofi Birthday 2025,
kita punya 3 merch dan sesuatu yang spesial dan voice. Mari kita lihat ya! Tan-tan!
we have 3 merch items, something special, and a voice pack. Let's take a look! Ta-dah!
Hai!
Yes!
ioDreaming Blanket! I'll keep you warm 24/7.
イオフィが暖かく包んであげるよ。こうやってぐっとね、暖かいからね。
Iofi will wrap you up nicely and keep you warm. Like this, tightly, because it's warm.
Nah, jadi kalau kalian, "Aduh dingin, perlu ditemani warm ini,"
So if you feel, "Oh it's cold, I need this warmth to keep me company,"
aku akan menemani malam-malammu yang dingin. Haha.
I'll keep you company on your cold nights. Haha.
で、今年もイラストは夜ノみつきママ！ありがとう！皆様もママありがとう！ーイ！
And this year's illustration is by Mitsuki-mama again! Thank you! Everyone, thank Mama! Yay!
Hai, lucu kali, fuwa-fuwa, kawaii~
Yes, super cute, fluffy, kawaii~
Eh, tapi kalau udah ada blanket, berarti kurang apa sih? Ah, NEXT!
Eh, but if you already have a blanket, what's missing? Ah, NEXT!
We have this one! Sweet Dreams Pillow Cover!
Jadi ini selain, ehem, tapi kayaknya kepala kalian bisa pas buat di...
So besides, ehem, I think your head will fit right...
Basically, it's so fuwa-fuwa, it's so comfy. You can place your head right in... yeah.
Basically, it's so fluffy, it's so comfy. You can place your head right in... yeah.
あの、これいいでしょ？こうやって... あ、そうそう！あ、でもでもでも...
Um, isn't this nice? Like this... Ah, right, right! Ah, but but but...
イオフィに夢中すぎてちょっと時間忘れちゃう... あ、ヤバい！どうしよう？っていう時はこちらです！
When you're so into Iofi that you lose track of time... "Ah, oh no! What should I do?", that's when you need this!
Hai!
Yes!
Jadi kalau kalian punya ini, enggak akan lupa waktu. "Aduh aku terlalu fokus sama Iofi, aku lupa waktu, Oh My God!" Ini!
So if you have this, you won't lose track of time. "Oh I was so focused on Iofi, I forgot time, Oh My God!" Here!
So you won't really forget about time while thinking about me, yeah!
可愛いでしょう？はい！
Isn't it cute? Yes!
あ、でもでもでも次次次次！次は... なんだなんだ？あ、はこちらです！はい、どうぞ！
Ah, but but but next next next next! Next is... what is it? Ah, it's this one! Yes, here you go!
Kini kita bisa ketemu di dalam mimpi! It's Dream Rendezvous,
Now we can meet in a dream! It's Dream Rendezvous,
so you will be meeting me in a dream. So...
夢でも会えるように、このボイスを聞いてね。はい！
So we can meet even in dreams, please listen to this voice pack. Yes!
では、あの、日本語、インドネシア語、英語、3つです。はい！
So, um, Japanese, Indonesian, English, there are 3 languages. Yes!
是非聞いてね！
Please listen to it!
Dan, dan, dan, tahun ini ada yang baru nih yang selalu ditunggu-tunggu nih. There's gonna be something new this year, and this is it! BAM!
And, and, and, this year there's something new that everyone's been waiting for. There's gonna be something new this year, and this is it! BAM!
If you buy the full version, there's gonna be a hololive CARD GAME! YEAH!
This is a bonus hololive card! Ini sebagai bonus pembelian full set premium.
This is a bonus hololive card! This is a bonus for buying the premium full set.
Premium merchandise. Ada kartu tambahan bonus kartu yang bisa kalian pakai di game-nya Official Hololive, guys! YES!
Premium merchandise. There's an extra bonus card that you can use in the official Hololive game, guys! YES!
You can actually use it on the on the game, yeah!
これでさ、大会とかで使ったらさ、めっちゃ自慢できますよ。こうやって、「うわっ！」
With this, if you use it at tournaments or something, you can brag so much. Like, "Whoa!"
「これがイオフィの限定の誕生日グッズから出たんや！」ほい！
"This came from Iofi's limited birthday goods!" Hoy!
でもまあ、お守りとしてもね、ここに置いてても大丈夫ですよ。イオフィがここにいるから。
But well, as a good luck charm too, keeping it here is fine. Because Iofi is right here.
Iya, jadi ini belum bisa dipakai di kartunya di game-nya,
Yeah, so this card can't be used in the game yet,
oshi Hololive card. Tapi kartunya hari ini yang ini sayang sekali baru ada bahasa Jepangnya. Jadi mohon pengertiannya ya.
my favorite Hololive card. But unfortunately, today's card is only available in Japanese so far. So please understand.
Untuk detail kartu dan cara bermain bisa dicek di homepage. Begitu, guys. Terima kasih!
For card details and how to play, you can check the homepage. That's it, guys. Thank you!
Dan kita sudah sampai di penghujung-ujung-ujung-ujung-ujung-ujung-ujung acara.
And we have reached the very, very end of the event.
Mm, jadi karena tahun lalu kita udah dengar "Here I Am" yang biasa,
Mm, so since last year we heard the usual "Here I Am",
nah tahun ini aku punya yang spesial untuk kalian.
this year I have something special for you guys.
"Here I Am" full Bahasa Indonesia!
"Here I Am" full Indonesian version!
Hai! "Here I Am" Indonesian version.
Yes! "Here I Am" Indonesian version.
Tapi itu hanya untuk membership.
But that is only for members.
Ya, mungkin 限定で "Here I Am" Indonesian version あとで歌います。
Yeah, so maybe as a member-exclusive I'll sing "Here I Am" Indonesian version later.
Hai, jadi habis ini akan... apa ya? Aku akan ketemu kalian di membership, oke?
Yes, so after this... what is it? I'll see you guys in membership, okay?
では、本当の本当の最後の曲になります。
Now then, this will be the real, real, real last song.
Hai, this will be my last song for tonight, hi!
Yes, this will be my last song for tonight, hi!
I hope you are ready!
This last song will be... 心の坂道
This last song will be... Kokoro no Sakamichi.
手話で
with sign language.
何回も苦しい思いをした
I've been through pain more times than I can say
何回も悲しい思いもした
I've felt the sorrow that wouldn't go away
今日までたくさん歩いてきた
Step by step, I've made it here today
心の坂道を
Up the hill where my feelings lay
歩き慣れた帰り道 突然転んだ
I tripped and fell on the road I always take
不意打ちみたいで
Caught off guard, like a sudden break
まるで裏切られた気分
It hit me like a stab in the back
...んだ
It hit me like a stab in the back.
破けたジーンズと
In torn-up jeans and
心の隙間に
a heart with a crack,
冷たい風が抜ける
the cold wind gently passes through.
小石蹴飛ばして
I kick a pebble as I move on too.
一歩踏み出すと
The moment I took a single step ahead,
君がいてくれた
I found you standing there instead.
何度も苦しい思いをした
I've been through pain more times than I can say.
何度も悲しい思いもした
I've felt the sorrow that wouldn't go away.
今日までたくさん歩いてきた
Step by step, I've made it here today,
心の坂道を
up the hill where my feelings lay.
君がいたから強くなれた
Because you were there for me, I found the strength to be.
傷だらけであの坂も歩けた
Even with scars, I climbed that hill with ease.
君がいるから歩いていけるさ
Because you're here with me, I know I'll keep walking free,
涙の足跡残さないで
leaving no tears for the world to see.
あの日君は言っていた
That day, you said to me,
「本当の強さは泣いてもまた笑えることだよ」
"True strength is being able to cry, then smile again, you know?"
何度も苦しい思いをした
I've been through pain more times than I can say.
何度も悲しい思いもした
I've felt the sorrow that wouldn't go away.
今日までたくさん歩いてきた
Step by step, I've made it here today,
心の坂道を
up the hill where my feelings lay.
君がいたから強くなれた
Because you were there for me, I found the strength to be.
傷だらけであの坂も歩けた
Even with scars, I climbed that hill with ease.
君がいるから歩いていけるさ
Because you're here with me, I know I'll keep walking free,
涙の足跡残さないで
leaving no tears for the world to see.
君がいたから
Because you were there for me,
君がいるから
because you're here with me.